Guide to the Maynard Mack Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Maynard Mack papers
1928-1997
YCAL MSS 111
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
62.28
(132 boxes) + 2 broadside folders, 6 cold storage
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Maynard Mack in the course of his scholarly and teaching activities, including extensive documentation relating to his research on Alexander Pope and Shakespeare. Research and writing files include notes, copies of archival material, card files, lists, drafts, page proofs, printed material, and related material. Teaching files include notes, lectures, and course material. Correspondence consists largely of single letters to Mack from literary figures, including James Angleton, Richard Eberhart, William Empson, Robert Graves, Allen Tate and Eudora Welty, as well as a small group of correspondence with Robert Penn Warren and two letters from T. S. Eliot to Helen Gardner and Robert Nichols. Other papers relate more broadly to Mack's activities and involvement with various professional organizations and projects.
Mack, Maynard, 1909-2001
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and bequest of Maynard Mack, 1994-2001.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for information about reference copies.
Biographical Overview
Maynard Mack received his B.A. in 1932 and his Ph.D. in 1936, both from Yale, and joined the English Department there in 1936, rising to become Sterling Professor of English in 1965. A scholar of Shakespeare, Pope, and twentieth-century literary criticism, Mack has authored a number of works, including King Lear in Our Time (1965) and Alexander Pope: A Life (1986).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Maynard Mack in the course of his scholarly and teaching activities, including extensive documentation relating to his research on Alexander Pope and Shakespeare. Research and writing files include notes, copies of archival material, card files, lists, drafts, page proofs, printed material, and related material. Teaching files include notes, lectures, and course material. Correspondence consists largely of single letters to Mack from literary figures, including James Angleton, Richard Eberhart, William Empson, Robert Graves, Allen Tate and Eudora Welty, as well as a small group of correspondence with Robert Penn Warren and two letters from T. S. Eliot to Helen Gardner and Robert Nichols. Other papers relate more broadly to Mack's activities and involvement with various professional organizations and projects.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1928-1991. II. Shakespeare Research, Writing, and Teaching, 1941-1979. III. Alexander Pope Research and Writing, 1936-1993. IV. Other Teaching Files, 1941-1973, 1993, V. Professional Papers and Other Research Material, 193850-1997.
English drama; English literature; English poetry; Poets, English -- 18th century -- Biography; Educators -- United States; Scholars -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Angleton, James, 1917-1987; Eberhart, Richard, 1904-2005; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Empson, William, 1906-1984; Graves, Robert, 1895-1985; Mack, Maynard, 1909-2001; Pauker, John, 1920-; Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979; Welty, Eudora, 1909-2001; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1928-1991; Series I; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Other papers and printed material are arranged at the end of the series.
  - Adams, Frederick B., Jr., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Lee, 1966 September 5 (Box 1)
  - Angleton, James, [circa 1940 January] (Box 1)
  - Bishop, John Peale, [circa 1939] (Box 1)
  - Bradley, George, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1941 April 20 (Box 1)
  - Empson, William, [1939] December 14 (Box 1)
  - Fitts, Dudley, Mrs., 1970 July 20 (Box 1)
  - Graves, Robert, 1961 July 25 (Box 1)
  - Kizer, Carolyn, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Mack, undated (Box 1)
  - Miller, undated (Box 1)
  - Miller, J.I., [1928?] (Box 1)
  - Pauker, John, 1949-1981; 6 (Box 1)
  - Tate, Allen, 1940-1946 (Box 1)
  - Warren, Austin, 1940 March 19 (Box 1)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1975-1978 (Box 1)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1977 April 29 (Box 1)
  - Yale University, Office of the Secretary, 1940 February 16 (Box 1)
  - Other papers and printed material
    - T. S. Eliot to Helen Gardner, 1961 October 11 (Box 1)
    - APcS to Robert Nichols, 1928 April 26 (Box 1)
    - First-day covers and staps related to Shakespeare, 1964-1976 (Box 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1931-1971; 2 (Box 1)
- Shakespeare Research, Writing, and Teaching, 1941-1979; Series II; 10.4; (23 boxes)
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series II is comprised of various groups of files stemming from Mack's research and writing on Shakespeare, as well as files relating to classes on Shakespeare that he taught. Similar material can also be found in Series IV, Other Teaching Files.
  - Shakespeare Edition: Reviews and Performances (author's folder somewhere), undated (Box 2)
  - Mehus Letter to Maynard Mack on Richard II Genealogical Table, 1979 January 5 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified Folder (Box 2)
  - MM Shakespeare - ed. Texts General, undated (Box 2)
  - MM Edition - All's Well That Ends Well, undated (Box 2)
  - Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 3)
  - A Y L I, undated (Box 3)
  - Coriolanus Paste Up, undated (Box 3)
  - MM Edition - Hamlet, undated (Box 3)
  - MM Text 2 Henry IV, undated (Box 3)
  - Henry V - MM ed., undated (Box 4)
  - Henry VI - Part 3, Paste-Up, undated (Box 4)
  - MM Text: King Lear, undated (Box 4)
  - MM Text: Love's Labor's Lost, undated (Box 4)
  - The Merchant of Venice, 1973-1993 (Box 5)
  - Measure for Measure, undated (Box 5)
  - Midsummer Night's Dream, 1953-1975 (Box 5)
  - Midsummer Night's Dream (J. O'Grady), undated (Box 5)
  - MM Text - Much Ado, Paste-Up, undated (Box 6)
  - Othello, Paste-Up, undated (Box 6)
  - MM Text: Richard II, undated (Box 6)
  - Richard III, Paste-Up, undated (Box 6)
  - MM Text: The Tempest, undated (Box 6)
  - Romeo and Juliet: Hayden, undated (Box 7)
  - MM Text: Timon of Athens, undated (Box 7)
  - MM Text: Twelfth Night, undated (Box 7)
  - MM Edition: Troilus and Cressida, undated (Box 7)
  - The Winter's Tale, Paste-Up, undated (Box 8)
  - Shakespeare Projects, 1959-1964 (Box 8)
  - Graduate Shakespeare, undated (Box 8)
  - English 127a, 1973-1974, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
  - English 127, 1969-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Principles of Drama, 1964, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Principles of Drama: New Graduate Course, 1961-1964 (Box 8)
  - Shakespeare: Organization of Course, 1953-1964 (Box 8)
  - Authorship of the Plays, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Shakespeare and Films, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Reader's Digest Shakespeare Records, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Tragedy and Shakespeare Tragedy: General, 1954-1961 (Box 9)
  - World of Shakespeare's Tragedies, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Mode of Existence of a Shakespeare Play: H. Gilliam and C.H. Frey, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Comedy (G.S. Reed), undated (Box 9)
  - Comedy and Shakespeare Comedy: General, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Elizabethan Theatre and Production of Shakespeare, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Shakespeare: Iconography, 1964 (Box 9)
  - English 34: Exams, 1950-1964 (Box 9)
  - English 34: Student Outline, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - English 35, 1954-1956 (Box 10)
  - Shakespeare: Introductory, 1947-1966 (Box 10)
  - Sonnets and Other Poems, 1947-1953 (Box 10)
  - All's Well That Ends Well, 1941 (Box 10)
  - Sage: Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 10)
  - Wellesley: Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 10)
  - Hawaiian: Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 10)
  - Antony and Cleopatra Lecture: 1) 1 hr 2) 45 min, undated (Box 10)
  - Outlines on Antony and Cleopatra: Tuppie Lecture, undated (Box 10)
  - Antony and Cleopatra Essay for Tuppie's Return, undated (Box 10)
  - Ms. of Antony and Cleopatra essay; original lecture, undated (Box 10)
  - All my Notes for Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 10)
  - Antony and Cleopatra paper: Ashby Crandall, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Antony and Cleopatra: Untitled, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Antony and Cleopatra Essay for Tuppey, undated (Box 11)
  - Antony and Cleopatra: Various Shakespeare Inst. Sheets and English 34, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Antony and Cleopatra: Eugene, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Antony and Cleopatra Essay: Masterset Paper, undated (Box 11)
  - MM - Carbon Copy, Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 11)
  - Tuppie: Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, undated (Box 11)
  - Students' Essays and Xeroxes on Antony and Cleopatra for Teaching Prospects, undated (Box 11)
  - As You Like It, 1972 (Box 12)
  - AYLI for Swarthmore, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Comedy of Errors, 1947 (Box 12)
  - Coriolanus, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Cymbeline, undated (Box 12)
  - Notes on Hamlet: Trumbull Lecture MS., 1952 (Box 12)
  - Hamlet, 1956-1968; 2 (Box 12)
  - MM - Scenario for PBS TV Hamlet, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Hamlet: J. Gezari, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Tragedy: T. Weiskel, 1968 (Box 13)
  - TV Hamlet: 1973, undated (Box 13)
  - CTCH Hamlet and Colie, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Hamlet: Ford Shakespeare Institute Hamlet, etc., undated (Box 13)
  - I - Henry IV, 1953-1973 (Box 14)
  - II - Henry IV, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Henry V, undated (Box 14)
  - Henry VIII, undated (Box 14)
  - Playbills, undated (Box 14)
    Includes King Lear, Much Ado About Nothing, Trolius and Cressedia.
  - Julius Caesar: text of MM edition, undated (Box 14)
  - Julius Caesar, undated (Box 14)
  - Julius Caesar notes, 1957 (Box 14)
  - King John, undated (Box 15)
  - King Lear, 1947 (Box 15)
  - King Lear: M. O'Connell, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Lear Paper for MLA 1960 (Box 15)
  - King Lear Outlines, undated (Box 15)
  - King Lear Temporary, undated (Box 15)
  - King Lear: English 34, 1954-1966 (Box 15)
  - J. Trombetta: King Lear cinematic adaptations, undated (Box 15)
  - Unfinished Lear Essay: Wellesley Lecture on Shakespeare, 1953 (Box 15)
  - King Lear: M.F. Edell, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Current King Lear, undated (Box 15)
  - Washington King Lear, undated (Box 15)
  - Sociality in King Lear, 1963 (Box 15)
  - King Lear: Elizabeth Keiser, 1964 (Box 16)
  - King Lear: Donald D. Knight, 1964 (Box 16)
  - King Lear: Leslie Epstein, undated (Box 16)
  - King Lear: G.S. Reed, 1965 (Box 16)
  - King Lear: J. Trombetta, 1970 (Box 16)
  - King Lear: R. Dellemora, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Love's Labours Lost, undated; 2 (Box 16)
  - Macbeth - text of MM ed., undated (Box 16)
  - Macbeth, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Othello: M. Frank, undated (Box 16)
  - Macbeth: M. Sprengnether, undated (Box 16)
  - Macbeth: Francine Malden, undated (Box 16)
  - Macbeth: C. Christ, 1968 (Box 16)
  - Measure for Measure, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Measure for Measure: J. Patrick, 1966 (Box 17)
  - Merchant of Venice, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Merchant of Venice: David Quint, undated (Box 17)
  - Merry Wives of Windsor, undated (Box 17)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, 1960-1979 (Box 17)
  - Othello, undated (Box 17)
  - Othello: L.-L. Marker, undated (Box 17)
  - Othello at Hartford, undated (Box 17)
  - Hofstra and other Othello fragments, undated (Box 17)
  - Othello: Clearson, undated (Box 18)
  - Othello: R.R. Macdonald, 1968-1974 (Box 18)
  - Othello, 1966-1976 (Box 18)
  - Pericles, undated (Box 18)
  - Richard II, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Richard II: Jean Humez, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Richard III, undated (Box 18)
  - Richard III: J.M. Speyer, 1965 (Box 18)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1961-1973 (Box 18)
  - Romeo and Juliet: Hayden introduction, undated (Box 18)
  - Monterallo: Romeo and Juliet, undated (Box 18)
  - Taming of the Shrew, undated (Box 18)
  - Tempest, undated (Box 19)
  - Washington - Tempest, undated (Box 19)
  - Tempest, 1951-1962 (Box 19)
  - Shakespeare's Tempest, undated (Box 19)
  - Timon of Athens, undated (Box 19)
  - Titus Adronicus, undated (Box 19)
  - Romeo and Juliet, undated (Box 19)
  - Troilus and Cressida, undated (Box 19)
  - Troilus and Cressidea: D. Harris, 1965 (Box 19)
  - Twelfth Night: Diane Janeau, undated (Box 19)
  - Twelfth Night: Leigh Holt, 1965 (Box 19)
  - Twelfth Night, 1939-1941 (Box 19)
  - Winter's Tale, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Winter's Tale: K. Vanden Berg, 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Winter's Tale: Nina Emerson, 1973 (Box 20)
  - Essay on Allusion, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Cartoons, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Lectures (empty), undated (Box 20)
  - Japan's Othello, Romeo and Juliet, Shakespeare Today, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Shakespeare in Our Time: NPR, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Shakespeare Acting: Modern Productions, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Staging: Miscellaneous, 1976-1979 (Box 20)
  - Pratt Institute: Othello and other plays, undated (Box 20)
  - Othello: Monterallo - Candles in the Dark, undated (Box 20)
  - Romeo and Juliet, undated; 2 (Box 20)
  - Shakespeare (Box 20)
    - Othello, undated (Box 20)
    - Shakespeare in Our Bones, undated (Box 20)
  - [Production of Shakespeare's Plays?] (Box 21)
    - Play Production, undated (Box 21)
    - Films - TV, undated (Box 21)
    - Shakespeare Edition: Audio-Visual and Other Resources, undated (Box 21)
    - All's Well That Ends Well, undated (Box 21)
    - Antony and Cleopatra, 1967 (Box 21)
    - As You Like It, 1950 (Box 21)
    - Coriolanus, 1965 (Box 21)
    - I: Henry IV, 1951 (Box 21)
    - II: Henry IV, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Henry V, 1966 (Box 21)
    - III: Henry VI, undated (Box 21)
    - Hamlet, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Julius Caesar, 1953 (Box 21)
    - King Lear, 1961 (Box 21)
    - Love's Labour's Lost, 1965 (Box 21)
    - Measure for Measure, undated (Box 21)
    - Midsummer's Night Dream, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Much Ado About Nothing, 1959 (Box 21)
    - Othello, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Richard III, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Macbeth, 1955 (Box 22)
    - Merchant of Venice, 1960 (Box 22)
    - Richard II, 1956 (Box 22)
    - Romeo and Juliet, 1960 (Box 22)
    - Tempest, 1968 (Box 22)
    - Timon of Athens, 1952 (Box 22)
    - Troilus and Cressida, 1961 (Box 22)
    - Twelfth Night, 1958 (Box 22)
    - Winter's Tale, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Other Plays, undated (Box 22)
    - Staging: General, 1964 (Box 22)
    - Questions and notes on Shakespeare, undated (Box 22)
  - Card Files (Box 22)
    - S.'s Text - Cymbeline, undated (Box 23)
    - Hamlet - LLW, undated (Box 23)
    - Macbeth - Sonnets, undated (Box 23)
    - Various Topics (Shakespeare), 1963-1968 (Box 23)
    - Shakepeare's Tragic World, undated (Box 24)
- Alexander Pope Research and Writing, circa 1936-1993; Series III; 36.1; (74 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  Series III is comprised of various groups of files stemming from Mack's research and writing on Alexander Pope, and includes extensive documentation relating to his 700-page biography, Alexander Pope: A Life (1986). Material related to Mack's research on Pope can also be found in Series IV, Other Teaching Files, and Series V, Professional Papers and Other Research Material.
  - Pope's Library
    - Pope's Library: List with MM, notes on some, undated (Box 25)
    - Addison, Joseph, undated (Box 25)
    - ? Alcorani, undated (Box 25)
    - Ariosto, undated (Box 25)
    - Bacon, Francis, 1958 (Box 25)
    - Barclay, Sir John, 1957-1974 (Box 25)
    - Barclay, Robert, undated (Box 25)
    - Barford, Richard, undated (Box 25)
    - Beaumont, Francis and Fletcher, James, undated (Box 25)
    - Bertius, 1971-1975 (Box 25)
    - Beza (or Beze), Theodore de, undated (Box 25)
    - Bible, the Holy, undated (Box 25)
    - Boccalini, T., undated (Box 25)
    - Bochart, Samuel, undated (Box 25)
    - Boileau-Despreaux, Nicholas, undated (Box 25)
    - Boyle, Robert: Medicinal Experiments, 1974 (Box 25)
    - Boys, John: Aeneid VI, undated (Box 25)
    - Breval, John Durant, undated (Box 25)
    - Burnet, Gilbert, undated (Box 25)
    - Butler, Samuel, undated (Box 25)
    - Cervantes, undated (Box 25)
    - Chaucer, Geoffrey, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Cicero, 1958 (Box 25)
    - Clarendon: History of the Rebellion, undated (Box 25)
    - Corporis Iuris Civilis, undated (Box 25)
    - Cudworth, undated (Box 25)
    - Cunaeus, Petrus, 1938 (Box 25)
    - Cunigamus (Cunningham), Alexander, undated (Box 25)
    - Curll, Edmund, 1958-1959 (Box 25)
    - Dacier, Mme, undated (Box 25)
    - Dalacourt, James, undated (Box 25)
    - Dart, John, undated (Box 25)
    - Davison, Francis, undated (Box 25)
    - Donne, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Dryden: comedies, tragedies, operas, 1971-1972 (Box 25)
    - Dryden, John, 1958-1970 (Box 25)
    - Epistolae Obscurorum Virorum, undated (Box 26)
    - Felibien, Jean Francois, 1939-1958 (Box 26)
    - Fenelon, Francois Salignac, undated (Box 26)
    - Fenton, Elijah, undated (Box 26)
    - Fitzgerald, Thomas, undated (Box 26)
    - Garth, Samuel, undated (Box 26)
    - Gay, John, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Glover, Richard, undated (Box 26)
    - Granville, George Baron Lansdowne, undated (Box 26)
    - Hall, Joseph, 1976 (Box 26)
    - Herbert, George, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Herodotus, undated (Box 26)
    - Hill, Aaron, undated (Box 26)
    - Hobbes, Thomas, undated (Box 26)
    - Homer, undated (Box 26)
    - Horatius Flaccus, Quintus, undated (Box 26)
    - Houbracken, J., undated (Box 26)
    - ? Huet, undated (Box 26)
    - Hume, David, undated (Box 26)
    - Jonson, Ben, undated (Box 26)
    - Juvenalis, Decimus Junius, undated (Box 26)
    - Pope: MS Notes on Dyden's Corrections of [Stephay]? Juvenal, undated (Box 26)
    - Langland, William, 1966 (Box 26)
    - Lindesay, Patrick, undated (Box 26)
    - Locke, John, undated (Box 26)
    - Lucanus, Marcus Annaeus, undated (Box 26)
    - Lucian, undated (Box 26)
    - Montaigne, undated (Box 26)
    - Montaigne, Michel de, undated (Box 26)
    - Opera et Frequente: Mattaire, Michael, undated (Box 26)
    - Lucretius Carus, Titus, undated (Box 26)
    - Lyttleton, Lord George, undated (Box 26)
    - Manilius, M., undated (Box 26)
    - Martialis, Marcus Valerius, undated (Box 26)
    - Milton, John, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Monier, 1958-1971 (Box 26)
    - Oldham, John, undated (Box 26)
    - Opus Cula Mythologica, undated (Box 26)
    - Ovidius Naso, Publius, undated (Box 26)
    - Paget, Thomas C., undated (Box 26)
    - Parnell, undated (Box 26)
    - Persius Flaccus, Aulus, undated (Box 26)
    - Philips, Ambrose, 1974 (Box 26)
    - Pindar, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Pitt, Christopher (Virgil), undated (Box 26)
    - Poems on Affairs of State, 1957 (Box 26)
    - AP: Libels on 1-24, undated (Box 27)
    - Two Bodley Oriental Mss, Pope's Gift, undated (Box 27)
    - Prior, Matthew, undated (Box 27)
    - Puckle, James, undated (Box 27)
    - Purchas His Pilgrims Pt. III 162, undated (Box 27)
    - Quintilianus, Marcus Fabius (Box 27)
    - Rochester, John Wilmot, Earl of, undated (Box 27)
    - Rowe, Elizabeth, undated (Box 27)
    - Rymer, Thomas, undated (Box 27)
    - Seneca, Marcus Annaeus, undated (Box 27)
    - Shakespeare, William, undated (Box 27)
    - Sidney, Philip, 1914 (Box 27)
    - Silvestre and Schenck ii, Alcune Vedute di Giardine, undated (Box 27)
    - Spenser, Edmund, 1966 (Box 27)
    - Stanley, Thomas, undated (Box 27)
    - Statius, Publius, undated (Box 27)
    - Tasso, undated (Box 27)
    - Terentius Afer, Publius, undated (Box 27)
    - Theocritus, undated (Box 27)
    - Thomas a Kempis, undated (Box 27)
    - Thomson, James, undated (Box 27)
    - Tickell, Thomas, undated (Box 27)
    - Tophail, Abu Bakr (ibn), undated (Box 27)
    - Touchet, G., 1957 (Box 27)
    - Valerius Flaccus, Lucius, undated (Box 28)
    - Velleius Paterculus, undated (Box 28)
    - Vida, Marcus Hieronymus, undated (Box 28)
    - Virilius Maro, Publius, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Wesley, S.: Iliad in a Nutshell, undated (Box 28)
    - Young, Edward, undated (Box 28)
    - Andreini, Giambattista, undated (Box 28)
    - Barrow, Isaac, undated (Box 28)
    - Berkeley, George, undated (Box 28)
    - Blackmore?, Richard, undated (Box 28)
    - Bramston, James, undated (Box 28)
    - Buononcini, undated (Box 28)
    - Chubb, Thomas, undated (Box 28)
    - Crashaw, Richard, undated (Box 28)
    - Denham, John, undated (Box 28)
    - Erasmus, Desiderius, 1957 (Box 28)
    - Thou, Jacques Auguste de (Thuanas), undated (Box 28)
    - ? Evelyn, John, undated (Box 28)
    - Gildon, C., undated (Box 28)
    - Hughes, John, undated (Box 28)
    - Plain Dealer: Hill, undated (Box 28)
    - Politian, undated (Box 28)
    - Sackville, Thomas, undated (Box 28)
    - James, Ralph, undated (Box 28)
    - Richardson, Jonathan, undated (Box 28)
    - Skinner, Stephen, undated (Box 28)
    - Smith, Samuel, undated (Box 28)
    - Thomson, James, undated (Box 28)
    - Thuanus, de Thou, 1971 (Box 28)
    - Vertot, Abbe de, undated (Box 28)
    - Voltaire, Francois M.A. de (empty), undated (Box 28)
    - Warburton, William, undated (Box 28)
    - Wesley, S.: Iliad in a Nutshell, undated (Box 28)
    - Whitehead, Paul, undated (Box 28)
    - Wollaston, William, undated (Box 28)
    - Uncertain Entries, undated (Box 28)
    - Apocryphal Entries, 1958 (Box 28)
  - Mapledurham Books Found Later Than 1938, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Xeroxed Letters and Miscellaneous Material, 1958 (Box 28)
  - Letters and Miscellaneous Materials, 1977 (Box 28)
  - Hartlebury Books Generally, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Lists Referring to Several Authors, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Books Once Popular but not Surviving, 1976 (Box 28)
  - Dissertations: Minute Book, 1968 (Box 28)
  - Addison, Joseph, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Allen, Ralph, 1966 (Box 29)
  - Amhurst, Nicholas, undated (Box 29)
  - Queen Anne, undated (Box 29)
  - Arbuthnot family, 1981-1983 (Box 29)
  - Atterbury, Francis, undated (Box 29)
  - Mrs. Barbor: poems, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Barclay, Robert, undated (Box 29)
  - Barnard, Sir John, undated (Box 29)
  - Bathurst, Allen, undated (Box 29)
  - Bathurst, Chester, undated (Box 29)
  - Bedingfield, Edward, undated (Box 29)
  - Bentley, Richard, 1963 (Box 29)
  - Birch, Thomas, undated (Box 29)
  - Bishop, Cecil, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Blackmore, Richard, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Bethel, Hugh, undated (Box 29)
  - Blount, Edward, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Boyle, Henry, undated (Box 29)
  - Blount Letters, undated (Box 29)
  - Blount letters continuted, undated (Box 29)
  - Blount Sisters
    - TB letters and personality, undated (Box 29)
    - Martha Blount, undated (Box 29)
  - Blount: TB and MB: documents (early), 1974 (Box 29)
  - Blount Sisters: Iconography, 1978 (Box 30)
  - Blount Family of Mapledurham, undated (Box 30)
  - Blount Family: MM notes and useful documents, 1969 (Box 30)
  - Boyle, John, undated (Box 30)
  - Boyle, Richard (ed. E.F. Burlington), 1972-1973 (Box 30)
  - Bridges, Ralph, undated (Box 30)
  - Broome, William, undated (Box 30)
  - Bruce, Charles, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Buckley, Samuel, 1989 (Box 30)
  - Budgell, Eustace (1686-1737), 1970 (Box 30)
  - Burnet, Gilbert, undated (Box 30)
  - Burnet, Thomas, undated (Box 30)
  - Burton, Simon (AP Physician 1690-1744), undated (Box 30)
  - Caesar, M. Adelmar, undated (Box 30)
  - Caesar, William, undated (Box 30)
  - Campbell, Archibald, undated (Box 30)
  - John Carteret (Earl Granville), undated (Box 30)
  - Cave, Edward, undated (Box 30)
  - Caesar, Charles, undated (Box 30)
  - Campbell, John, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Caryll, John Sr., 1970 (Box 30)
  - Churchill, John (Duke of Marlborough), undated (Box 30)
  - Churchill, Sarah, undated (Box 30)
  - Cleland, William, undated (Box 31)
  - Codrington, William, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Cole, Natheniel, undated (Box 31)
  - Conduitt, John, undated (Box 31)
  - Congreve, William, undated (Box 31)
  - Cooke, Thomas, undated (Box 31)
  - Cotterell, Clement, undated (Box 31)
  - Cowper, Judith (Mrs. Madan), undated (Box 31)
  - Craggs, James and Anne, undated (Box 31)
  - Cromwell, Henry, 1980-1981 (Box 31)
  - Curll, Edmund, undated (Box 31)